<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title> - Privacy</title>
	<link href="https://jtodak.github.io/my-blog/tags/privacy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://jtodak.github.io/my-blog/"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2020-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://jtodak.github.io/my-blog/tags/privacy/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How much will we pay for privacy</title>
		<published>2020-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://jtodak.github.io/my-blog/how-much-will-we-pay-for-privacy/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jtodak.github.io/my-blog/how-much-will-we-pay-for-privacy/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the new adage goes, you either pay for the product or you are the product. 
Nowhere is this more true than in online spaces, where we gladly trade eyeballs and more recently earlobes for content.
And it makes sense, since ads were, and still are the most practical way to monetize web content, but we are headed for a fork in the road. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better understand it, lets quicky go thru the history of the modern consumer internet. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1990 - 2000 The small bang, just getting our toes wet&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dec 12, 1991 - The first website in the US goes live&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oct 1994 - HotWired, the first web site to sell banned ads in large quantities &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall - The first pop-up is created &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1998 - First Google index, 26 million websites&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 - 2008 The Cambrian explosion and the rise of social media&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2003 - Wordpress, iTunes and Myspace are launched &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2004 - Facebook launched &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2005 - YouTube launched&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2006 - Twitter launched &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2007 - iPhone Launch&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2008 - Lunch of the Apple App Store with 500 apps &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2008 - 2020 The brave old world, we are the products. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, Facebook, Baidu, Twitter, Amazon, Instagram, etc are the top online destination. 
Thanks to the popularity of smartphones we are always connected, we turn to google for answers, we go to amazon to become fulfilled, Instagram and Facebook for social recognition, Youtube for entertainment. We live thru our phones and our apps. And it&#x27;s all free to a certain extent.
The digital ad industry is worth about 350 billion dollars annually, and its all payd for by selling our data to advertisers. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where do we go from here, where do the two roads lead? 
I think it&#x27;s simple. The internet (just like the world) will be split in two. The haves and the have nots. 
The haves will essentially pay for privacy, think Netflix vs YouTube, or Apple&#x27;s ecosystem vs Android. If you are willing and can pay for the services you consume, there is no need for ads, privacy will become the next big selling point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile the have nots of the world, will continue to consume, but they will either pay a lower price, only subsidized or continue consuming the products and pay for it with their attention. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a kind of symbiosis, the haves generating profits for companies, while the have nots will generate growth and top line revenue. Kind of like the matrix, only if people powering the machines had a two-tiered system. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no moral standing whether this is right or wrong. The point is that we will have to pay for privacy, and privacy will become the next big buzzword in tech. We can already see Apple putting privacy on the forefront.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy is coming, the question is who will be willing to pay and how much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
